Guide to the Robert Landy Papers MC.259
New York University Archives
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Drama/Theatre for/with the Elderly, 1979; cuid5168
  Guests include Bonnie Robbins and Paula Gray.
  - Audio, cuid5168 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5168)
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 32)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Drama/Theatre in the Deaf Community, 1979; cuid5169
  - Audio, cuid5169 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5169)
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 33)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Drama/Theatre in the Black Community, 1979; cuid5170 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5170)
  Guests include Ellen Cleghorne and members of The Family.
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Drama/Theatre in the Black and Hispanic Communities, 1979; cuid5171
  Guests include Marvin Felix Camillo and Rose Calavido.
  - Audio, cuid5171 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5171)
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 34)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Theatre for Children #1: The Playwright, 1979; cuid5173
  The guest is Aurand Harris.
  - Audio, cuid5173 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5173)
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 35)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Theatre for Children #2: The Producer/Director, 1979; cuid5164
  The guest is John Clark Donahue, founder and director of Minneapolis' Children's Theatre Company. Donahue discusses his background in children's theatre and what he emphasizes at the Children's Theatre Company, in particular working in classics and having formal instructors.
  - Audio, cuid5164a (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5164a)
  - Video, cuid5164b (Box 21, U-matic MC.259.cuid5164b)
    Original cassette is labeled John Clark Donahue SS #10.
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 36)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Theatre for Children #3: The Actors, 1979; cuid5174
  Guests include Judith Martin and Irving Burton.
  - Audio, cuid5174 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5174)
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 37)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Puppetry in Education, 1979; cuid5175
  The guest is Maurice Stewart.
  - Audio, cuid5175 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5175)
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 38)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Puppetry, Mask, Mime, Myth, 1979; cuid5176 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5176)
  The guest is Tom Miller.
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Process Drama and Theatre Reviewed, 1979; cuid5177
  The guest is Brian Way.
  - Audio, cuid5177 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5177)
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 39)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Career Opportunities in Educational Drama, 1979; cuid5178 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5178)
  Guests include Lowell Swortzell and Vera Mowry.
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Future Directions: A Preview of Things to Come, 1979; cuid5179 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5179)
  Guests include Ann Shaw and Nellie McCaslin.
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Summary and Conclusions, 1979; cuid5180 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5180)
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Untitled, 1981; cuid5181 (Box 20, Quarter inch audio reel MC.259.cuid5181)
  Labeling on original package reads: Sunrise Semester Drama M26 dubbed 6-3-81.
- Teaching -- Sunrise Semester -- Southern Africa Civilizations in Turmoil, 1979
  These recording consist of two lectures by Professor Richard W. Hull for the Sunrise Semester series on Southern Africa: Civilizations in Turmoil.
  - South African Unification, cuid5182 (Box 21, U-matic MC.259.cuid5182)
    Original container labeled: Ep. # H-15 Richard W. Hull.
  - Reaction to Conquest: Asian Resistance, cuid5183 (Box 21, U-matic MC.259.cuid5183)
    Original container is labeled: Sunrise Semester H-14.
- Teaching -- T - V, 1983-2015; cuid5212
  - Paper Records (Box 13, Folder 1-8)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_10
- Theatre -- A - K, 1971-2001; cuid5188
  - Paper Records (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_15
- Theatre -- Letters from Sing Sing, 1994-2010
  - Paper Records, cuid5189 (Box 2, Folder 1-9, Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_1
- Theatre -- Lo - Padrone, 1972-2015; cuid5190
  - Paper Records (Box 3, Folder 2-15, Box Shared University Archives 050, Folder 7)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_9
- Theatre -- Padrone - Ph, 1978-1980; cuid5191 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
- Theatre -- Rags to Riches, 1975; cuid5185; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel Original reel is labeled: Rags to Riches rough draft. (Box 4, Folder 8-9, Box 23, Folder 4-7)
- Theatre -- S - Y, 1969-1983; cuid5192 (Box 4, Folder 10-19, Box 23, Folder 2-3)
- Trainings -- A - Da, 1996-2011; cuid5198
  - Paper Records (Box 9, Folder 13-15)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_11
- Trainings -- Dr. Robert J. Landy Drama Therapy Seminar, 1995
  - Video, cuid5122; 5 VHS Original container for cassette MC.529.cuid5122b is labeled: Lecture: "The Image of the Mask"; and the original container for cassette MC.529.cuid5122a is labeled: Lecture #1: "Training the Drama Therapist". (Box 18, Cassette MC.259.cuid5122a-e)
    The video recordings consist of lectures given by Landy in Taiwan, performances by students, and a closing event for the seminar. Landy speaks English which is translated into Mandarin by different people throughout the recordings. Landy lectures about drama therapy and psychotherapy history, different drama therapy methods, the state of drama therapy in the United States, the use of masks in rituals throughout the world, and answers questions from class.
  - Paper Records (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
- Trainings -- Drama Therapy A - Drama Therapy W, 1998-2010; cuid5199 (Box 9, Folder 18-22)
- Trainings -- An early dialogue about the meaning of drama therapy, 1982; cuid5129; 1 VHS (Box 18, Cassette MC.259.cuid5129)
  Landy lectures on the roles of the drama therapist, psychotherapist, and psychoanalyst. A class discussion follows.
- Trainings -- Ec - Is, 2002-2011; cuid5200 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
- Trainings -- Lo - N, 1994-2009; cuid5201 (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
- Trainings -- Reach for Speech, 1985-1989
  - Video, cuid5126; 1 videocassette (Box 18, Cassette MC.259.cuid5126)
    Access to the video recordings is restricted until the University Archivist determines whether access can be provided.
    The video recording consists of New York City Schools Chancellor introducing the Reach for Speech program to New York City teachers and students performing as characters and giving speeches.
  - Paper Records (Box 10, Folder 9-11)
- Trainings -- Res - Workshops in England, 1990-2010; cuid5202 (Box 10, Folder 12-22)
- Trainings -- Workshop in Korea, 1990-2012; cuid5131; 1 VHS (Box 10, Folder 23)
  Label reads: Healing Ceremony / Village Ceremony by Youjin Hong July 9 90 Korea
- Unidentified video reel, Undated; cuid5186 (Box 22, Reel MC.259.cuid5186)
- Writings -- A - F, 1975-2016; cuid5193
  - Paper Records (Box 5, Folder 1-20)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_6
- Writings -- God Lives in Glass, 1997-2006
  - Video, 1997-2006; cuid5133; 1 VHS (Box 18, Cassette MC.259.cuid5133)
    Consists of a performance by Landy and children of God Lives in Glass and Is Shaped by the Wind.
  - Paper Records (Box 7, Folder 6-16, Box 8, Folder 1-7, Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_4
- Writings -- God Lives in Glass -- Children's artwork, interviews, and performances, 1998-2016
  Repository permission is required for access. Please contact the University Archives, university-archives@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2641.
  - Video, cuid5132; 1 videocassette (Box 18, Cassette MC.259.cuid5132)
    The recording includes Landy asking children to describe how they see God and asks them to play games, tell stories, and draw pictures about God.
  - Paper Records (Box 14, Folder 1-17, Box 15, Box 16, Folder 1-18, Box 17, Folder 1-5, Box 24, Folder 1-3)
  - Electronic Records, UA_MC_259_ER_8
- Writings -- H - Ta, 1970-2009; cuid5194 (Box 5, Folder 21, Box 6, Folder 1-23)
- Writings -- Three Approaches to Drama Therapy, 2005-2006
  - Video, cuid5134; 1 VHS (Box 18, Cassette MC.259.cuid5134)
    This recording is similar to that on MC.259.cuid5128. Landy introduces the lecture on Everett L. Shostrom's 1965 Three Approaches to Psychotherapy and his work to create a modern version of this for drama therapy. Landy demonstrates role method and role theory, David Reed Johnson demonstrates developmental transformations, and Nina Garcia demonstrates psychodrama. The recording ends with a performance by students acting out dialogue of the patient in the three methods.
  - Paper Records (Box 6, Folder 24, Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Writings -- Three S - W, 1982-1994; cuid5195 (Box 7, Folder 3-5)